PRINCE COBBY AMOATEY

American House, East Legon, Ghana | 0558605427, 0209788337 | princeamoatey21@gmail.com | DOB: 11-07-1995

CAREER PROFILE / OBJECTIVES

A hardworking individual with years of combined experience in Technology support, Web application Development IT Service Management, hardware and software maintenance and configurations. Proven self-starter who is highly organized, prioritizing and multitasking to achieve work. Team player with a track record of establishing productive work relationship.

EDUCATION / CERTIFICATIONS

Ghana Technology University College Greater Accra - Ghana BSc.
Information Technology August 2013 - June 2017

Pope John Senior High School Koforidua - Ghana General Arts September 2010 - May 2013

Certified Ghana Greater Accra - Ghana

MCSA: Windows Server 2012 CERTIFICATE August 2019

Ramsys Info Solutions Greater Accra, Ghana Ethical Hacking Certification August 2020

WORK EXPERIENCE

Amalitech Ghana September 2022 – Present Junior Front-End Developer

- Created two web applications from figma design files.
- Implemented Responsiveness of the web application I created to enhance user experience
- Fixing Bugs and performing code maintenance to ensure efficiency.
- Communicated with back-end developers for any front-end problematic issues.

Capsol Technologies Limited – Accra, Ghana Technical Consultant

Nov 2020 - Present

- Provided pre-buy and post-buy technical support for software product client purchased.
- Domain configurations and hosting
- Installation & configuration of requested software & hardware solution.
- Training and educating clients on specific and new aspect of the platform and related solutions
- Performed technical solutions over zoom and team viewer.
- · Performed Data recovery and network resolutions
- Responded to all client requests in a timely manner to ensure continuous business operation.

Agricultural Development Bank – Accra, Ghana IT Support Officer (National Service)

- Provided daily, weekly and monthly reports on tasks completed and issues resolved.
- Managing Users with Active Directory.
- Led a five-man team in the administration of computer hardware and software solutions.
- Handle troubleshooting within an enterprise environment, including network downtimes, system crushes, slowdowns and data recoveries
- Provided testing and technical evaluation of hardware and software solutions.
- Maintained inventory of hardware and software available and kept track of their locations & assessed asset lifecycle.
- Primary point of contact for all hardware and software related enquires and worked collaboratively with colleagues in administration of support, software development and regulatory to address issues that arose.
- Performed hardware and software research to assess efficiency in the use of computer resources and new hardware introduced & asset acquisition.
- Ensured constant availability of network services to enable banking servers run efficiently.

Expresso Telecommunications Limited – East Legon, Accra, Ghana **Technical Support (Intern)**

May 2016 - August 2016

- Assisted team lead to handle technical/mission-critical calls daily and consistently met high service standards.
- Assisted team lead to provided technical assistance in the installation of routers and switches in the server room.
- Performed routine checks on the network stability at various stations and towns.

REFERENCES

Mr. Frank Ebo Quansah

Senior Database Infrastructure Engineer eProcess International S.A(Ecobank Transnational Incorporated) 0249243711

Mr. Fawzy Issifu

Assistant Manager, I.T Department National Petroleum Authority 0243265453

Mr Joseph Patterson

Head of I.T Department Agricultural Development Bank 0277184686